[Music]
and so neurologically you can say to
somebody things nicely but what if
they're from courtesans offline but it's
overwhelmed by cortisol yeah so again
you know it's legitimate that we should
support people taking responsibility but
it's important to ask what's in the way
of that and how we help them get there
let's look at that's a real question and
you have spent a lot of time with these
patients so that with addicted patients
in your work well with myself and with
yourself yeah I find it quite
interesting that you have explored the
shadow side of humanity and therefore
know so well how desperately we need
tools of transformation yeah and how
many people are stuck and could be
liberated if there was another way so I
find it quite striking then how you
discovered psychedelics which are tools
for transformation and can yeah they're
among the tools is the in the right
settings liberate us and the rigidity of
our thoughts for sure
now of course spiritual modalities the
pathways of all kinds from way before
the Buddha to the present time have
asked the same question agent Greeks
know and and Greece Pythagoras
Socrates so these questions have been
asked for a long long time
certainly one powerful and in my
experience effective pathway for a lot
of people not for everybody
excuse me is the route of psychedelics
precisely because they get underneath
the defenses that we built up in
childhood and they get to the core of
the issues that motivate us but they
also can take us down to that real stuff
that we've been talking about people who
actually experienced their real selves
may reveal the true being of a being
absolutely that can happen to people
which doesn't mean that having study
being revealed to you therefore you can
know
badi it so there's a you know you're
gonna have this great experiences and
and as my wife could tell you we're back
to being the same jerk that you were
before the experience unless there is
unless there's integration honestly deep
immersion unless there's a practice
around it but as a way of revealing
these truths and and and helping people
transform really psychedelics or in the
right context I need to emphasize that
under the right guidance in the right
context right leadership right
counseling right integration they can be
extraordinarily effective mmm so they
said a few things their environment our
preparation intention then integration
these are all vitally important to the
outcome and how changed you are from a
psychedelic experience health how much
you do recover from of yourself and one
thing that really helped me at your
workshop at cyclic science 2017 was the
focus you put on the creation of an
intention and recently be going quite
deep in Buddhist practice and I've been
discovering that the same thing applies
for what is practice you're encouraged
to stay fuel made it your intention to
meditate each time you meditate so quite
I'd love for you to share some of the
thoughts and some of the reflections you
would consider when recommending someone
create an intention for a psychedelic
experience so if you look at the root of
the word intention it comes in Latin
were a ten year which is to stretch or
tener at the stretch so intention is
something that you wanna stretch towards
internally that you want to move towards
like an agency it's like exactly yeah
that's right yeah that's cool that's
right
so when you want to suck it like
experience you can just I just want the
trip season colors I see some nice
colors and interesting animals or
whatever so as people do or you can have
an intention that's related to your
personal development
now somebody might go into the ceremony
wanted to get to know their fear show me
my fear really get to teach me about my
fear or teach me about love or teach me
about show me my power or help me
understand my childhood or whatever the
intention isn't and it's not when I work
with people it's that we don't set a
general intention for the whole group we
help people identify their intention
individually each for themselves and the
intention is not like a weight that you
carry on your neck that has to burden
you it's an anchor though that you can
keep keeps that keeps you moving in a
certain range and you keep coming back
to it because throughout the ceremony
you Michael all these different states
and then you want to come back to your
intention yes an intention without
expectation intention without
expectation without a rigid attachment
[Music]